University of Connecticut 1998.0247
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Charles B. Gentry, 1928-1929]
undated, 1928-1969.
1998.0247
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.0 Linear feet
Charles Burt Gentry was educated at the University of Missouri and came to Connecticut from Rutgers University in 1920. He became Dean of the Division of Teacher Training in 1921, and, after his term as acting president (1928-1929), served as the director of the Division of Instruction and as Dean of the University. Gentry retired in 1950.
University of Connecticut. President's Office.
Biography
Charles Burt Gentry was educated at the University of Missouri and came to Connecticut from Rutgers University in 1920. He became Dean of the Division of Teacher Training in 1921, and, after his term as acting president (1928-1929), served as the director of the Division of Instruction and as Dean of the University. Gentry retired in 1950.
Scope and Content
The records consist of the general correspondence of the President of the College. It is the only extant collection of the papers of the president for this period. The correspondence is concerned with internal administrative matters, major policy issues at the college, with the college's relations with state and federal governments, and with other educational agencies and institutions. Also included is a collection of correspondence presented to Mr. Gentry on the event of his retirement from the University and a small folder of correspondence with the Gentry family pertaining to the naming of the Gentry Building.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Correspondence ( undated, 1928-1929 ) includes correspondence, publications, reports, and similar records pertaining to the day to day operation of the institution.
Series II: Retirement Correspondence ( 1950 ) contains a bound volume of correspondence presented to Mr. Gentry on the occasion of his retirement from the University of Connecticut.
Series III: Building Naming ( 1967-1969 ) includes correspondence between University administrators and the Gentry family pertaining to the naming of the Gentry Building.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The records of the President's Office from 1908 to 1935 were stored in Gulley Hall until about 1960, when they were relocated to the attic of Beach Hall. In 1968 they were brought to the Special Collections Department.
Acquisition Information
The records were transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives in August 1979 and were arranged and described in the spring of 1980. In 1995, Special Collections and Historical Manuscripts and Archives merged to form Archives & Special Collections and were relocated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center. In 2001, the Presidential records were reprocessed and separated by presidential tenure.
Gentry, Charles Burt, 1844-1955.; Administrative Records.; College presidents—Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Notes.; Obituaries.; Universities and colleges—Administration.; Universities.; University of Connecticut. Office of the President.; University of Connecticut—History.; University of Connecticut—Presidents.
- Series I: Administrative Correspondence, undated, 1928-1929
  - Accrediting of C.A.C., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Buckley, John (Trustee), 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Carillon—general file, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Chase, Thornton, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Chimes— J.C. Deagan, Inc., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Church—Trustees, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Classroom Building (Beach Hall), 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Eaton, Edwin C., undated, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - G, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Greene, Arthur F. (Trustee), 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Gumbardt, Edward H. (Economics), 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - History of College, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Hollister, S.P., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Hough, Clifford E. (Trustee), 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Housing accommodations for students, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Insurance (college buildings), 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Land Grant Colleges, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - M, 1928-1929, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Manchester, H.G. (Trustee), 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - P, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - R, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Retirement, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - S, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Skinner, A.G., 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Slate, W.L., 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Stemmons, Walter, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Student enrollment and other statistics, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Student Organization—Constitution, By-laws, undated (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - Student publications, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - T, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Tax Commissioner, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Veterans Hospital, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
- Series II: Retirement Correspondence, 1950
  - Letters (Bound Volume), 1950
- Series III: Building Naming, 1967-1969
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 1:, Folder 34)